

Being an enthusiastic Software Engineer which is both problem solving and creative, a bachelor holder in Computer Software Engineering from the Faculty of Engineering and Technology (FET) in the University of Buea, having 3+ years in software development. Versed in programming languages such as PHP, PYTHON, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL, and Java

# NDIMBU COURAGE MAH

#### **Profession:**

Software Developer

#### **Status:**

Single

#### Phone:

+237 673722729 +237 620288022

#### E-Mail:

ndimbucourage@gmail.com

## **Country:**

Cameroon

## Residence: Yaounde Ngousso, Stade Balla

#### Languages

- English
- French

## **Experience**

08/2021 to 10/2022

#### Back-end:-

### Bridge Africa Ventures

Worked in Bridge Africa ventures as a backend engineer, on a project whose purpose is to provide business visibility online as well as giving the various businesses, users, and they community they all form to communicate and have the possibility to market their products and users able to purchase. For this project in the backend API call I made used of LARAVEL.

Useful Links: https://bridgeafrica.com

09/2020 to 01/2021

## Front-end and Back-end:-Bright World Group Ltd

Carried an internship in BW Group to build an app for streaming. Streams consisting of radio, TV, Podcast, and Audio Books. For the front-end the Ionics framework was used and for the back-end the Laravel Framework(Laravel Admin Panel).

Useful Links: http://bwstreams.com

06/2020 to 07/2020

### Front-end and Back-end:-University of Buea

Worked on the Front-end and Back-end of the school project which was based on building an app for a school management system, programming languages used were HTML/CSS, PHP, and a little of SQL

02/2020 to 02/2020

#### Front-end:-

#### Zouix

A Hackathon which was organized by DevCircle Buea in partnership with Zouix, which aimed at building a car tracking system for the company. Programming languages used for the

## **Projects**

- Business Communication Online Directory a 3 in 1 (SAAS): Using LARAVEL framework for API calls.
- Stream Manager: Using the Laravel Admin Panel framework to build a stream manager that manages information concerning various radio streams.
- Buid an Address Book with LARAVEL.
- Worked on an Ionics framework. To manage the various API calls from a Laravel Admin Panel.
- Covider: A platform to monitor and track distribution of amenities and basic need to the population during the COVID-19 pandemic. Build in both web (REACT NATIVE) and mobile.
- A Messaging System: A platform where students could send and receive messages. Build in JAVA.

## **Education**

2017-2021

 Bachelor of Computer Engineer: Software Engineer -University Of BUEA, SW

2014-2016

• Advance level: Lycee Essos (GBHS Essos, Yaounde)

Mathematics: B
Further Mathematics: C
Physics: D
Computer Science: D

2009-2014

• Ordinary Level: Lycee Bonaberi (GBHS Bonaberi, Douala)

Mathematics: C
Physics: C
Economics: C
Computer Science: C
Chemistry: C

## **Skills**

- Back-End programming languages: PHP, PYTHON, JAVA
- Back-End Framework: LARAVEL, Spring Boot
- Front-End programming languages: HTML, CSS and , JavaScript
- Front-End Framework: IONICS, BOOTSTRAP 5, and REACT Js
- CMS: WORDPRESS
- Databases: SQL/ MySQL
- Version control: Git, Bitbucket
- API / Rest tools: Postman, Insomnia
- Self-Motivated
- Creativity
- Analytical skills
- Time management
- Team work